HARDIK PATEL

(226)-898-6840 | <u>hardikpatel00079@gmail.com</u>

CAREER SUMMRY

I am a Software Developer with 3+ years' experience in java Programming Language, have a post-graduate diploma in IT Business Analysis, and bachelor's degree in information technology engineering.

Specialties: Web Development and Programming, (JAVA, C, C++), Angular, REST API, Spring boot, Typescript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Consultant

FDM Group 2022 – Present

- Collaborated with other Developers, and Business Analysts, participated in initial brainstorming for architecture design (ER diagram, UML, Use Case etc.)
- Backend JAVA Development, Designed database structure, table relationships
- Used OOP concepts such as inheritance, abstraction etc. in development.
- Developed REST API with CRUD capability using java spring boot and MySQL.
- Wrote SQL, HQL and named queries.
- Used log4J for logging and debugging, Junit and Mockito for testing
- Worked in Agile Project Management Environment.

Web Developer

Bluepixel Technologies, India

2018 - 2019

- Designed and developed the client management solution for a home maintenance company. Collaborated with team and project manager on initial brainstorming of the solution, architecture, and project requirements in Agile scrum model.
- Front-end development using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Back-end development leveraged JAVA and JavaScript

Software Developer (Internship)

Maxgen Technologies, India

2016 – 2017

- Worked on a Java-based web development project called ERP(Enterprise Resource Planning). This ERP monitors an organization's planning and management, such as payroll, attendance, income, and expense reporting.
- Developed Front-end and back-end using HTML, CSS, Java, and JavaScript
- Presented a demo of Application in the Techfest event at Gujarat Technological University which allowed me to develop my communication and presentation skills.

TECHNICAL QUALIFICATIONS

Programming Languages: C. C++, Java

Web based languages/Technologies:

HTML/CSS, Typescript, Core Java, OOP, ORM

Software Applications: Microsoft 365(Excel,

Word, Access, Power Point,

Analytics: Power BI, Gephi, Excel, Data

Analysis, Business Analysis.

Testing: Selenium, Cucumber, Mockito, Junit.

Database Management: Database SQL

commands, MySQL.

Operating Systems: Mac OSX, Windows, UNIX

Collaboration tools: GitLab, Jira, Confluence. **Framework:** Spring Boot, JUnit, Mockito,

Angular, Agile Project Management

Cloude Tech: AWS, AZURE Fundamentals.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Web Development

Self-Learning and Development

2021 - Present

- Backend- Development in JAVA, JPA, Spring boot and REST Api.
- Frontend HTML, CSS, Typescript, Angular
- ❖ Used OOP concepts such as inheritance, abstraction etc. in development.

1. Academy Report Portal

Tech Stack/Technologies: Spring Boot, Maven, Spring MVC Angular, MySQL

- Academy Report Portal is portal for student, instructor and recruiter, where instructor can be able to generate report on particular student which is accessible by the recruiters.
- Project Link

2. Virtual Voting System

Tech Stack/Technologies: Spring Boot, Maven, Spring MVC Angular, MySQL

- Virtual Voting System is a voting web service where employee can easily vote for candidates of the company e.g., Employee of the Month, Consultant of the Month.
- Project Link

AWARDS

Microsoft Student Ambassador (2020 -2021)

Received awards on completion of course and organizing teaching webinar. Worked for Microsoft Student Community.

EDUCATION

Conestoga College, Kitchener, Canada

2019 - 2021

Post – Graduate Diploma (2 Years)

Information Technology Business Analysis | 3.4/4 GPA

Gujarat Technological University, Ahmedabad, India

2013 - 2017

Bachelor of Engineering

Information Technology Engineering | 7.61/10 CGPA